STEPHANIE FOSKITT

Buffalo, NY 14203 • (716) 416-8602 • Stephanie.Foskitt@gmail.com

Work History

Senior Software Engineer, 03/2022 to 09/2024

Cox Automotive – Burlington, VT

- Developed an ETL pipeline to filter 800,000 records per month using Snowflake, AWS services and Vertica
- Modified the monolithic back end service to accommodate the 10 new endpoints required to query and retrieve the new ETL data
- Wrote Terraform code required to create the AWS infrastructure for the ETL
- On-call support and debugging for the existing Kubernetes containers running on AWS EKS
- Led the team migrating an existing Confluent data pipeline to AWS Kafka pipeline
- Contributed to conversion from Jenkins CI/CD to GitHub Actions by writing actions and workflows for 6 repositories
- Mentored junior engineers and incoming team members

Software Engineer II, 04/2017 to 02/2022

Bizrate Insights, a Meredith Company - Los Angeles, CA

- Back end microservice and API development in Java with Spring (2020-2022)
- Front end development with React (2017 2020)
- Heavy AWS infrastructure development in EC2, CodeDeploy, S3, Lambda, API Gateway, CloudFormation and more
- Maintenance of existing services and scripts in Python
- Familiarity with Zeppelin, Airflow, SonarQube and more

Front End Developer, 10/2015 to 02/2017

Vroozi – Los Angeles, CA

- Test-driven feature development and bug fixes for the company's primary product, Purchasing Manager, using AngularJS 1.5, NodeJS, MongoDB, and Jasmine
- Research issues on the company's secondary product, SmartOCI, and provide recommendation for fixes

Software Developer I, 09/2013 to 02/2015

National Western Life Insurance Company – Austin, TX

- HTML/CSS/Javascript changes to external company web sites upon request from Marketing and Underwriting departments
- XLNT scripting for ActiveBatch job automation, development and management
- Active management of 15-20 products and state-required insurance forms on SQL database with Microsoft SQL Server
- Wrote Javascript code that validated HTML against an XML list of agents' ID numbers to produce alternative text on company's external website based on user login
- Track down and squash bugs in 2.5GB C# code base using Visual Studio 2013

Skills

- AWS Services including: Lambda, EC2 (minimal here, maximal at Bizrate), RDS, Aurora,
 DynamoDB, S3, Athena, EMR, MSK (managed streaming for Kafka), Glue, Step Functions,
 EventBridge, SNS, SQS, EKS, AppSync,
 CloudFront, Route53, API Gateway, Secrets
 Manager, IAM, CloudWatch
- Soft skills: Excellent written and verbal communication skills, team leadership, creative problem solving, collaboration within and outside the team, accountability and adaptability
- Languages: Java, Javascript, React 16, Python, Scala
- Other Technologies: Snowflake, Terraform, SonarQube, Airflow, Spring Boot 3, GitHub Actions, Kafka

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, 08/2023

Texas State University - Round Rock, TX

Completion: Advanced Software Engineering, 05/2015

MakerSquare Immersive - Austin, TX

MOS 74B: Information Technology, 05/2000

U.S. Army Advanced Individual Training - Fort Gordon, Augusta, GA

Projects

Cox Auto nVision

- Auto dealership sales, inventory, and advertising data aggregated and rendered in a visualization web app
- Primary responsibilities were in the back end data pipeline, ETL, and monolithic service layers.

Bizrate Insights Vital Signs

- Online retailers' shopper survey data aggregated and rendered in a visualization web app
- Responsible for both front-end React components and reports, as well as the back-end microservice modifications and database maintenance

Vroozi Purchase Manager

- Procure-to-pay platform for B2B procurement transactions
- Feature development and bug fixes
- TDD with Jasmine and Mocha

Summary

Hardworking software engineering professional with 12 years experience. Ready and motivated to find the next outstanding who is ready and motivated to find the next challenge.

Objective: Make outstanding contributions on an outstanding team creating outstanding products.